YAKINI ARUMUGA KANI

South Jordan, Utah 84095
Phone: 508 494 3722 | Email: yakinilatha09@gmail.com
LinkedIn | GitHub | Portfolio

SUMMARY

Full Stack Web Developer with basic knowledge in testing and also a self-motivated professional who likes to solve problems. I have worked as a performance tester with substantial hands on experience in Apache JMeter scripting, performance testing and java programming. I am a passionate web developer and tester who can easily collaborate with other team members and project managers to accomplish the project and quality goals.

Core competencies: HTML, CSS, Materialize, Bootstrap, jQuery, Node JS.

Manual testing, Performance testing, Mobile application testing, Java Programming, Selenium, TestNG, JIRA, MySQL, JMeter, Eclipse. New Relic, Loggly, Banking, e-Learning, Credit Analysis.

Certifications: ISTQB CTFL certified Tester

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER

MAY 2020 - CURRENT

Bootcamp at University Of Utah

Full Stack Web Developer with the knowledge to build responsive websites that focus mainly on rich user experience. Gained more development skills in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, React.js, NodeJS, Express, etc. I implemented a space exploration website and helped the team in resolving the issues with responsive behavior and applied proper styling using Materialize CSS to make it more user friendly.

RECENT PROJECTS

Space Exploration | GitHub | View Online

Mobile-focused web app where users can explore, and know about the space related stuff from NASA API. Some of the features including NASA photos, Live Hubble View, Near Earth Objects, Mars Weather, Planet Information are being implemented.

Responsibilities:

I implemented the front end of the application by using HTML, Materialize CSS. I also developed the homepage of the application which includes Custom Google Search and displays the videos from the NASA API that changes frequently. Focussed in achieving the responsiveness on various devices with the help of both Materialize CSS and media queries.

Also took initiative in solving the problems faced by my teammates including coding challenges as well as in resolving the conflicts faced on Github.

Weather Dashboard | GitHub | View Online

Mobile-focused web app where users can see the weather details of a city. Uses Weather API for displaying the weather details of the city where the user can enter a city name or select one. All the back-end and front-end were completely done by me as this is an individual project.

FRUGAL TESTING INC

Remote Worker

Performance Test Engineer

2019 - 2020

Manual Testing Projects: Middle East Corporate, Zoom

- Understood the requirements and functional specification of the application.
- Written a detailed Test plan, Test Scenarios, Test cases and Test Data based on requirements.
- Interacting with Client on Weekly status calls.
- Reviewed the test cases written by colleagues and made corrections as needed.
- Manually tested the website in Internet Explorer, Google Chrome, Firefox, iPhone Safari.
- Created the defects with the complete screenshots taken and also performed the defect analysis and re-testing for the open bugs.

Performance Projects: Money On Mobile, Learnwise, CRC, Impuesto

- Identifying Performance testing Scenarios from the set of flows identified in cycle.
- Developing Performance Test Cases for the identified testing Scenarios.
- Performed Correlation, Parameterization and Assertion for the developed test cases.
- Reviewed the Code prepared by other teammates and suggested improvements if required
- Running tests and analyzed the report file for errors.
- Looking into New Relic to identify bottlenecks.
- Analyzed log files and produced reports based on the Analysis.
- Prepared overall performance report for the client based on complete analysis of the test.

COGNIZANT TECHNOLOGY SOLUTIONS

Chennai, India

Programmer Analyst

2011 - 2013

- Developed Java code for Customer and Merchant applications.
- Written Junit test cases and ensure its coverage by applying the various test design techniques such as boundary value analysis, decision table, state transition, etc.for the developed Java code.
- Performed Integration and System testing.
- Also, performed system level tests using Rest Client and SOAPUI.
- Executing and reporting done after the test run.

ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE

2014 - 2017

Worked on opening an ECommerce store to sell party supply items online. Also involved in performing SEO to boost up the sales and did promotion on social media sites including facebook, pinterest.

2018 - 2019

Worked on Manual as well as Automation Testing projects. Used Selenium and TestNG framework to perform automation testing on websites.

EDUCATION

University Of Utah May 2020 - Current

Full Stack Web Developer Bootcamp

Crescent Engineering College 2006 - 2010

Bachelors in Engineering